<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Adam Freisinger</title>
  <subtitle>Explore, Create, Inspire</subtitle>
  <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/" />
  <updated>2026-01-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Adam Freisinger</name>
    <email>hello@adamfreisinger.me</email>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Photo of the Year</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2026-01-02/photo-of-the-year/" />
    <updated>2026-01-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2026-01-02/photo-of-the-year/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I had one of my photographs printed in a larger format, on proper fine art paper, and hung it on the wall of my living room. I treated it as if it were part of a small, private gallery: carefully placed, given space, allowed to exist as more than just an image on a screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was also the year I decided not to buy a Christmas tree. Instead, I made one from sticks and rope. It could be assembled, disassembled, and reused year after year, without cutting down another tree for a few days of decoration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was looking for a good place to hang one of the 2D ornaments, the hanger of the photo turned out to be the best spot. So I took the picture off the wall, fully intending to put it back once the holidays were over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the holidays ended, the year turned, and something unexpected happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the new year came a kind of quiet excitement. Instead of rushing to put the same photograph back, I found myself thinking about what it would be like to live with a different image for the year ahead. One that felt right for now. One that could set a tone, rather than just fill a space. And just like that, a small ritual was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, every year, when the Christmas ornaments are packed away, I look through my own photographs. I wait for one to speak to me. When it does, I have it printed, and it becomes one of the focal points of my living room—and, indirectly, of my daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spot matters. The image is visible not only when passing through the room, but also from the dining table and from my bed. I start my days with it. I end my days with it. For a whole year, we look at each other countless times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, this is my own, very personal “photo of the year” award. One I give quietly, without juries or votes or announcements. And in return, the photograph gets to shape my days. Sometimes subtly, sometimes more directly, simply by being there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year, I chose a submerging bird to accompany me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/photo-of-the-year-thumbnail.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/photo-of-the-year-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A bird submerging into water&quot; title=&quot;Photo of the Year 2026&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Photo of the Year 2026&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Notes on the object itself&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The print is made as a giclée on 100% cotton, acid-free, gently textured Hahnemühle Photo Rag Baryta paper. It’s mounted on aluminium dibond, without any framing. A hanger and spacers are glued to the back, so the shadow cast by the print itself becomes an ever-changing frame, depending on the light and the time of day. When choosing the print&#39;s size, I usually aim for a resolution of around 240 PPI.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Re-building My Music Library</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-12-02/rebuilding-music-library/" />
    <updated>2025-12-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-12-02/rebuilding-music-library/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;For a long time, music was something I didn’t just listen to. I lived &lt;em&gt;with&lt;/em&gt; it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew the exact moment when a scratch on one of our LPs would line up with the music. I could hear it approaching like a tiny, familiar glitch in the timeline. I made mixtapes on cassette, waiting with absurd patience for a song to come on the radio so I could catch it without the host talking over the intro. I knew precisely when to flip the tape in my walkman so I could replay my favourite song without rewinding and draining the batteries. Later, with my discman, I could predict whether a bump on the bus would be within the tolerance of the prebuffered stream or if it would choke. I had a growing CD collection, then a growing mp3 collection. I scrobbled everything compulsively to last.fm. On long car rides I’d get goosebumps from the tracks that were playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the way, that relationship got diluted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Streaming and the quiet erosion of attention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not anti-technology. I love good tools. But the shift to streaming did something subtle to my connection with music.
With “everything” available at all times, it became very easy to listen to “something”. I stopped tending to a library and started just consuming a feed. Music moved from being a carefully chosen companion to becoming background radiation. Playlists appeared out of nowhere. Algorithms tried to guess what I wanted. The friction almost completely disappeared.
In theory, that should be great. In practice, it made my relationship to music feel less personal. I rarely listened to an album from start to finish. I didn’t know which track was number 3 anymore, or where the emotional high point of an album lived. I wasn’t building anything; I was just tapping “next”.
And I missed that older version of myself: the one who would happily spend an entire evening fine-tuning a mixtape for someone, or sit on a bed with a stack of CDs, deciding which seven could come on a trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What I want back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d like to reintroduce a slower kind of discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to stumble onto new music that feels like a golden nugget. Something that makes me move or smile or go quiet for a bit. Something I want to listen to on repeat for days or weeks, then forget, then rediscover later and get hit by the whole package again: the sound plus the memories plus the person I was when I first heard it.
I don’t need a perfectly complete or objectively good music collection. I want a &lt;em&gt;personal&lt;/em&gt; one again. A library that looks like a strange, accurate map of my life at different points in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/rebuilding-music-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/rebuilding-music-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A shuffled album cover art gallery&quot; title=&quot;A glimpse to my current collection&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A glimpse to my current collection&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LPs, rituals and limits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I tried to fix this by going back to vinyl.
LPs did help in some ways. Putting a record on is automatically a ritual: choosing it, taking it out of the sleeve, placing the needle, committing to listening to a whole side. I still enjoy this, and I’d like to keep that as a special thing.
But LPs are expensive, take up physical space, and for me they are tied to being at home and having time and energy for the ritual. That combination makes it less accessible than I&#39;d like to.
Also, discovery through LPs alone is too limited for me. I’m not going to casually buy five random LPs just to see if one of them sticks.
So LPs stayed in the “beautiful, occasional ritual” category, not the “everyday music companion” one. Whenever I attend a live concert, I try to get my hands on an LP to have a memory capsule of the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Bandcamp and ripping the old shelves&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next iteration was Bandcamp plus local downloads.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;Bandcamp&lt;/a&gt; is a good compromise: it supports artists directly, I can actually own the music, and I can download high-quality files. Discovery is manual and scattered, but at least I’m picking things with intention. I’m paying attention to album art, labels, tags, and recommendations from people whose taste I find similar.
Lately I’ve started going backwards in time: I’m ripping my old CDs.
Not all of them. Just a few selected pieces at a time – the albums that were once important enough to buy and keep, even when money and shelf space were both limited. I’m using iTunes (or Music.app, or whatever the name is this year) and ripping them to lossless, which turns out to be pleasantly straightforward.
There’s something nice about the slowness of this process. Taking a CD out of its case after years, noticing the tiny scratches and fingerprints, remembering the weird local shop where I bought it. Dropping it into the drive. Hearing it spin. Watching the track titles appear, or not appear, and then having to fix them (for tagging I use &lt;a href=&quot;https://picard.musicbrainz.org/&quot;&gt;MusicBrainz Picard&lt;/a&gt;, which is somewhat less fiddly than it sounds,and my current choice for music playback at home is &lt;a href=&quot;https://swinsian.com/&quot;&gt;Swinsian&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;A tiny player with real buttons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other key piece was getting a dedicated music player again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/rebuilding-music-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/rebuilding-music-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A digital music player on the go&quot; title=&quot;Karnivool comes to Budapest in 2026 🥳&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Karnivool comes to Budapest in 2026 🥳&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought a Snowsky Echo Mini and bumped its storage with a 256 GB microSD card. Fifteen years after my last iPod shuffle retired, I have a small object in my hand that is &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; for playing music. No notifications, no messages, no browsers. Just files and buttons.
I can press play in my pocket. I can skip. I can pause. I don’t have to unlock anything or look at a glowing rectangle. It feels oddly freeing and very nostalgic at the same time.
I copy over the albums, the few carefully chosen things. It’s not “everything”. It’s my current small universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Yes, it takes more effort&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this more work than opening Spotify and tapping on a personalised playlist? Absolutely.
Ripping CDs, organising folders, tagging files with Picard one by one, hunting down missing covers. All of that takes time. Finding new music that actually catches my attention takes multiple tries. But that album that did catch my attention, now means something again.
Because I touched it. I decided to include it. I know which folder it lives in, which track feels like the core, and where I first listened to it. The friction makes me care again.
Do I feel more connected to the music I listen to now? Hell yes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a manifesto against streaming. I’ll probably still use it for certain things: quick checks, background playlists, sharing links. But next to that, I want to slowly re-grow a small, dense, personal music library that I handle with my own hands.
Something I can carry in my pocket, not because it contains all the music in the world, but because it contains just enough of the right music for &lt;em&gt;me&lt;/em&gt;, right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ginkgo Notebook</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-10-20/ginkgo-notebook/" />
    <updated>2025-10-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-10-20/ginkgo-notebook/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This year was heavy with woodworking, and lately, lighter crafts started calling me again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A carved lino block&quot; title=&quot;Carving can be so satisfying&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Carving can be so satisfying&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I carved a ginkgo leaf from lino—it turned out surprisingly decent for a first try. Then I bound a small A6 notebook: cardboard covers, Rives textured paper, simple pamphlet binding with waxed thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-hero.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Notebook and paper printed with lino block&quot; title=&quot;Fresh from the workbench&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Fresh from the workbench&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without a paper guillotine, I trimmed the edges by hand and rounded each corner one by one. I stamped the ginkgo on the cover with black paint, and apart from a single rogue fingerprint, it came out just as I’d hoped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s simple, fits in my hand perfectly, and makes me excited to see what I’ll fill it with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/ginkgo-notebook-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A6 notebook with a lino-printed ginkgo leaf cover, and some chestnuts in the front&quot; title=&quot;Ginkgo Notebook&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Ginkgo Notebook&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>A Logic Game from Leftover Wood</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-09-20/logic-game-from-leftover-wood/" />
    <updated>2025-09-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-09-20/logic-game-from-leftover-wood/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A few days ago I came across a logic game I had never seen before. I’m always curious about games, and this one struck me as both simple and ingenious. The rules: each piece has four dimensions (height, shape, colour, hollowness), and the goal is to get four in a row sharing any single dimension. The twist is that you don’t place your own piece, rather you choose one for your opponent (since then, I&#39;ve learnt that the name of the game is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quarto_%28board_game%29&quot;&gt;Quarto!&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of curiosity, I asked a friend to introduce me to resin printing, and recreating this game from my Shapr3D plans was a perfect first project. I quickly realised I still dislike the feel of plastic, so I decided to build a wooden version instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Resin printed prototype&quot; title=&quot;Resin printed prototype&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Resin printed prototype&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project gave me several firsts. I had never created a rod before, and now I managed one using a roundover bit, pushing a slat against a simple router fence, shaping some leftover aniegre. For the game board, I found a piece of cherry that was just the perfect size, and carved it by hand with a V-bit. Later, I improvised a small container from birch offcuts, on which the game board could double as a lid. That was my first time using a guide bushing with the router instead of a templating bit with a bearing. Next time, I’ll probably take out most of the material with a forstner bit first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Making a rod from a rectangular slat with a roundover bit&quot; title=&quot;Satisfying shaping of a rod&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Satisfying shaping of a rod&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-03.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some game pieces on the game board before sanding and finishing&quot; title=&quot;Starting to take shape&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Starting to take shape&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered various hinge mechanisms for the lid, but magnets have always fascinated me. I embedded small neodymium magnets, carefully aligning all four pairs, so that the lid can snap onto the base from any direction. It works beautifully, though I’ll remember not to try fitting the magnets next time before sanding and finishing again. Once inside, they refused to come out by any non-destructive way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-04.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Various things upon smaller things acting as a press&quot; title=&quot;My professional &quot; zen&quot;=&quot;&quot; press,=&quot;&quot; holding=&quot;&quot; the=&quot;&quot; magnets=&quot;&quot; in=&quot;&quot; place=&quot;&quot; until=&quot;&quot; PU=&quot;&quot; glue=&quot;&quot; cures&quot;=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;My professional &quot;zen&quot; press, holding the magnets in place until the PU glue cures&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the piece is finished, I find it lovely to look at and satisfying to interact with. It turned out polished in some ways, while still carrying the imperfections that make it unmistakably handmade. I enjoy the interplay of three different woods and the two pigments, the contrast of rounded and rectangular features, and the satisfying snap of the magnets. It makes me smile every time I pick it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-hero.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/logic-game-from-leftover-wood-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Logic game Quarto! made of wood&quot; title=&quot;I love the interplay of patterns, shapes and colours&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;I love the interplay of patterns, shapes and colours&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Piano Keys in Oak: A Coat Rack That Refused to Be Ordinary</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-09-03/live-edge-coat-rack/" />
    <updated>2025-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-09-03/live-edge-coat-rack/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What began as “just a coat rack” for a new fitness room quickly turned into something far more personal. The set included a modern oak shoe rack and a dining-style oak tabletop, but this piece became the wildcard: equal parts design experiment and personal challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-08.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The assembled oak coat rack with hooks folded out&quot; title=&quot;I loved making this one&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;I loved making this one&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the lumberyard, I stumbled upon an oak slab with a striking live edge. It wasn’t part of the original plan, but the moment I saw it, I knew I had to keep that raw, organic contour. It meant extra work and custom solutions, but it also promised a chance to make something truly mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An oak slab with a live edge&quot; title=&quot;A live edge that demands attention&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A live edge that demands attention&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hinge system was its own adventure. Before committing to oak, I started with real &lt;em&gt;CAD&lt;/em&gt; but later I turned to another flavour of CAD that stands for &lt;em&gt;Cardboard Aided Design&lt;/em&gt;. Prototyping the folding motion with cardboard, then refining it in plywood, gave me the confidence to move on to solid wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-05.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cardboard prototype of the coat rack mechanism&quot; title=&quot;Another type of CAD - Cardboard Aided Design 😅&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Another type of CAD - Cardboard Aided Design 😅&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-07.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The piano mechanism working smoothly&quot; title=&quot;It works!&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;It works!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only after the plywood template felt right did I commit to oak. The mechanism itself is simple in principle but demanding in execution: each hook folds out like the keys of a piano, disappearing flush when not in use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The small pieces laid out in order&quot; title=&quot;Ordnung muss sein! :D&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Ordnung muss sein! :D&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-04.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A CAD drawing of the coat rack mechanism copied to plywood&quot; title=&quot;CAD version 1.0&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;CAD version 1.0&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-06.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The piano mechanism taking shape&quot; title=&quot;Looking good so far&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Looking good so far&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting there meant meticulous, almost meditative cycles of assembly, reassembly, sanding, finishing, and testing again. Every adjustment was a respectful discussion with the material: avoiding cracks, respecting the grain, and finding harmony between precision and the organic irregularity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-03.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First rough assembly of the oak pieces&quot; title=&quot;Starting to take shape&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Starting to take shape&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I lifted the finished piece above my head for the hero photo, I realised it had become more than a commission. It was a synthesis of many things I care about: careful craft, playful engineering, and, above all, the meeting of function and aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-hero.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/live-edge-coat-rack-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Live edge oak coat rack held high above head&quot; title=&quot;I really am proud of this one&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;I really am proud of this one&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it hangs as a statement piece and a quiet reminder: even in everyday objects, beauty and utility can coexist—sometimes all it takes is patience, persistence, and a live edge you refuse to cut away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Crafting My Own Fregoli: A Ceiling-Mounted Drying Rack from Wood</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-03-09/wooden-fregoli/" />
    <updated>2025-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-03-09/wooden-fregoli/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My drying rack was always practical—but oh, how it irritated me. Its plastic wheels never cooperated, and every threshold became a battle of rattling metal and collapsing legs. One day, as I struggled with it yet again, I thought, &amp;quot;There has to be something better that takes up less floor space.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the &amp;quot;fregoli&amp;quot;—a traditional Hungarian ceiling-mounted drying rack from my childhood. But commercial options disappointed me—either ugly plastic contraptions or overly complicated motorised units priced like sports cars. And the memories also weren’t great: nylon cords frayed and tangled, the constant threat of falling, and a user experience so frustratingly poor it felt like punishment every time. Surprisingly, this very memory sparked my inspiration. Could I create something practical, beautiful, and enjoyable to use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the initial CAD sketches looked promising, transferring the plans onto the actual wood felt strangely off. Trusting my instincts, I kept the geometric logic but adjusted the spacing parameters on the fly. I&#39;m discovering more and more how important it is for me to plan thoughtfully, yet still leave room for improvisation and intuitive choices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of drawing tools&quot; title=&quot;I enjoyed geometry classes as a teenager 🤷‍♂️&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;I enjoyed geometry classes as a teenager 🤷‍♂️&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many curves, arches, and rounded corners, I initially cut the first piece freehand using a jigsaw and sanded it meticulously until it felt just right. I then used this piece as a template for the rest, routing them precisely with a templating bit. Realising how effortlessly I could reuse the leftover freehand-cut edges for subsequent pieces was incredibly satisfying—a tangible indicator that my jigsawing and routing skills have genuinely leveled up through steady practice. This step felt particularly important, marking a clear increase in my confidence thanks to continuous learning and practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Photo of cut out pieces&quot; title=&quot;Template in action&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Template in action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the lumberyard, I stumbled upon heat-treated oak dowels: a deep, rich colour, and a comforting scent intriguingly reminiscent of something I could not place my finger on yet. Paired with the leftover birch plywood, I envisioned the striking contrast between the dark rods and the plywood’s layered edges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-03.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of birch ply and heat-treated oak&quot; title=&quot;Beautiful contrasts&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Beautiful contrasts&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanding the rods was something I dreaded initially, but building a simple jig around an inverted orbital sander turned a tedious task into a surprisingly efficient one. Hours into the process, I realised why the smell seemed so oddly familiar: heat-treated oak first smells like something freshly baked, then immediately like some very luxurious whiskey. That sensory discovery alone made the tedious sanding feel worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-thumbnail.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-thumbnail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of wooden drying rack details&quot; title=&quot;Oiling is always satisfying&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Oiling is always satisfying&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favourite design detail: a sliding centrepiece. I wanted stability without sacrificing the flexibility to dry larger towels or sheets. By slightly widening the centre holes, I achieved a snug yet adjustable fit for the oak rods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-04.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Masking tape on the inner surfaces&quot; title=&quot;Trying to avoid some sanding&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Trying to avoid some sanding&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, there were unexpected challenges. Double-sided tape wasn’t strong enough to hold the pieces together for template routing, forcing me to improvise with screws that doubled as very handy centre markers. And when one oak rod snapped due to a hidden knot, the spare piece I instinctively bought saved the day—even presenting me with an opportunity to test whether PVA glue will bond to heat-treated oak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-05.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembled drying rack&quot; title=&quot;All glued up&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;All glued up&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mounting the rack was a saga in itself. After hours drilling into the stubborn ceiling, dodging iron rebars, and getting mortar in my ears, the pulley system finally held securely. It was exhausting, and something I&#39;m not really looking forward to doing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-07.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The bike lift plate is fixed to the ceiling&quot; title=&quot;There, I fixed it.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;There, I fixed it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the completed fregoli and feeling the texture of the wood fills me with quiet satisfaction. Sure, there are a few details I&#39;d approach differently next time, but right now, I&#39;m resisting the urge to immediately chase perfection. I&#39;m enjoying the imperfect beauty of what I’ve created, content in knowing that it already brings me joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-06.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Assembbled drying rack with hooks and cord&quot; title=&quot;Testing mounting options&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Testing mounting options&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lifting the rack for the first time was not the moment satisfaction hit me, but the next day, when I stepped into the room and saw how it transformed the whole atmosphere. The contrasting woods, the arching crosspieces, and the black lift strings create an intriguing shape resembling the ribcage of some graceful sea creature, casting intricate, ever-changing shadows across the room. The hardoils need a few weeks of curing to completely seal the woods from moisture, and now I find myself looking forward to laundry days, simply for the joy of interacting with something I&#39;ve made with care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-hero.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/wooden-fregoli-hero.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ceiling-mounted wooden drying rack in use&quot; title=&quot;In a nutshell – it&#39;s mounted!&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;In a nutshell – it&#39;s mounted!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating this drying rack was particularly meaningful because it marked my first entirely original design—not a remix, nor inspired by something I&#39;d seen elsewhere. Having the freedom to draw directly onto the wood, cut freehand, and make intuitive changes on the fly was liberating. It feels like a personal milestone: a confirmation that I can create something with confidence, from concept to finished object, that will live up to my (sometimes unrelenting) standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some friends asked if I’d consider making more to sell. But part of me knows the joy lies in the creation itself—the planning, the woodworking, the problem-solving—not in mass production. Sure, I might enjoy creating another one, perhaps refining the process, working more efficiently. But by the third repetition, I suspect I&#39;d already be redesigning it for CNC manufacturing and finding ways to simplify construction for outsourcing. Honestly, I&#39;d rather just share the design files openly online, making it accessible for others to replicate and improve freely. Maybe this makes me a terrible businessman—but I’m very much at peace with that idea. Perhaps that’s a good lesson learned: the things I love most lose their charm when mass-produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here it hangs—useful, elegant, mine. A reminder that surrounding myself intentionally with beautiful things that reflect back the qualities I want to nurture in myself is a worthy aspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Waving My Hand and Hearing Sound Respond in Real-Time</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-23/microbit-and-plugdata/" />
    <updated>2025-02-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-23/microbit-and-plugdata/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;plugdata&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two weeks, I’ve been diving into &lt;a href=&quot;https://plugdata.org/&quot;&gt;plugdata&lt;/a&gt;, a modern reimagining of Pure Data, a &amp;quot;visual programming environment designed for sound experimentation, prototyping, and education&amp;quot;. If you&#39;ve ever been fascinated by modular synths, interactive sound design, or generative music, plugdata makes these ideas instantly accessible, so it instantly won me over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It offers the same enjoyment for me that working with modular synthesizers (both in the physical world and via emulations like &lt;a href=&quot;https://vcvrack.com/&quot;&gt;vcvrack&lt;/a&gt;) or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://empresseffects.com/products/zoia&quot;&gt;Empress Zoia&lt;/a&gt; always had. I love modular thinking—connecting objects, seeing the flow of information—and plugdata aligns perfectly with that mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Catalyst: A Local Workshop on Electronic Instruments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been experimenting with music, instruments, and coding for years, but two weeks ago, I stumbled upon a three-part &lt;a href=&quot;https://adapterujbuda.hu/hangszerepito-kurzus/&quot;&gt;electronic instrument workshop&lt;/a&gt; nearby. The first session introduced the fundamentals of sound synthesis in &lt;a href=&quot;http://cycling74.com/&quot;&gt;Max&lt;/a&gt;—and just like that, I was all in again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop reignited something in me—this desire to build something that exists outside of a traditional computer setup, something tangible and expressive. That led me down a rabbit hole of research into embeddable systems that could support the kind of instruments I want to build. That’s how I landed on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://electro-smith.com/products/daisy-seed&quot;&gt;Electrosmith Daisy Seed&lt;/a&gt;, a powerful microcontroller designed for audio applications. It can host Pure Data patches (converted to C++), meaning I could eventually run my creations as standalone instruments—no laptop required. That vision became my new north star. But before I could get there, I wanted to test something simpler: how motion could shape sound in real-time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bringing Motion into the Equation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After spending hours patching in plugdata, I wondered—what if I could control sound with motion? I had an early version of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://microbit.org/&quot;&gt;micro:bit&lt;/a&gt; lying around, which has a built-in accelerometer. The idea was simple: use the XYZ coordinates of the micro:bit&#39;s accelerometer to modify parameters in my patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this work, I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;flashed a custom JavaScript program onto the micro:bit to continuously send accelerometer data,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ran a Python script using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pypi.org/project/python-osc/&quot;&gt;python-osc&lt;/a&gt; to translate motion data into a format plugdata can read, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;modified my plugdata patch to receive, filter, and scale the motion data to control sound in real-time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of MakeCode editor&quot; title=&quot;MakeCode editor for uploading to micro:bit&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;MakeCode editor for uploading to micro:bit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-02.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of Visual Studio Code&quot; title=&quot;The Python bridge script sending data&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;The Python bridge script sending data&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-03.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/microbit-and-plugdata-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A screenshot of plugdata&quot; title=&quot;The plugdata patcher receiving parameters&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;The plugdata patcher receiving parameters&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Tiny Card, a Big Feeling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, it worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9 block&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;has-ratio&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JhcDPnzj3jU?si=D3seO8Nk-e73dnZJ&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lifted my hand, tilting the tiny card ever so slightly. Instantly, the sound shifted—trembling, bending, shimmering—like a living thing responding to my touch. For a moment, it felt like I was sculpting sound in mid-air. Pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3QtklTXbKUQ&amp;amp;t=689s&quot;&gt;Imogen Heap’s Tiny Desk performance&lt;/a&gt;, where she demonstrated her MiMU gloves. That performance was one of many inspirations that planted a seed in my mind years ago—of making music in a way that feels fluid, intuitive, and physically expressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Code &amp;amp; Patch Downloads&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For anyone interested in taking a closer look at this setup, find my experimental code and patcher &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/freegyes/db35bc8d0b530abe511fdf8a1d54cdd7&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Takeaways &amp;amp; Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a small experiment, but it opened up so many possibilities. What if I combine this with other sensors? What if I replace the micro:bit with a more powerful and versatile device? What if the instrument I eventually build is less about pushing buttons and more about sculpting sound in space?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was just a small wave of my hand, but it felt like a giant step toward something bigger—an instrument that blends woodworking, sound, coding, and visuals into something truly expressive. I’m hooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;If You’re Curious&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Max, Pure Data, or plugdata sounds like your kind of thing, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.takumiogata.com/&quot;&gt;Takumi Ogata&lt;/a&gt;’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1o5Wasmd8yU&amp;amp;list=PLyFkFo29zHvD4eRftIAjcLqIXCtSo7w8g&amp;amp;ab_channel=SoundSimulator&quot;&gt;Sound Simulator YouTube series&lt;/a&gt; has been my main guide so far, and I can’t recommend it enough—and if you end up experimenting with it, I’d love to hear what you create.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Background Birds – A Collection of Nine Bird Portraits as Wallpapers</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-16/background-birds/" />
    <updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-16/background-birds/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Somewhere in the rhythm of my life, birds have been a quiet, constant presence. Perched on branches, gliding through open skies, or simply watching the world with that sharp, knowing gaze—these small creatures have a way of reminding me to pause and notice. And when I do, I unconsciously smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; title=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birds fascinate me—not just for their movement and freedom, but for the intricate details in their feathers, the way they observe their surroundings, and the quiet moments they allow when I stop to notice them. Over time, I’ve captured a set of bird portraits that I keep on rotation (a little round robin, if you will) as my desktop background. They bring a sense of stillness, curiosity, and fleeting connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birds, for me, have always been tied to rhythm and story—both in nature and in the music that has accompanied my thoughts on them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wholeheartedly recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://hiddenorchestra.bandcamp.com/album/wingbeats&quot;&gt;Hidden Orchestra’s Wingbeats&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a stunning piece of music, and what makes it even more special for me is that the birds are treated as an individual instrument in the released source tracks on the album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_RZpphITFM4&quot;&gt;Laurie Anderson’s The Beginning of Memory&lt;/a&gt;, a moving imagining of how memory was born.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a way, this collection is part of that same thread—something fleeting, yet worth holding onto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-07.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; title=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These birds have been my quiet digital companions for years, shifting with light and mood. Now, I’d love to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Download the Collection&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No fuss—no sign-ups, no emails, just the birds:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;➡️ &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/digital_downloads/background-birds.zip&quot;&gt;Download Background Birds (.zip)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;A Little More About This Collection&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This curated set includes nine high-resolution images (available in 16:9 and 16:10), detailed enough to appreciate yet subtle enough to sit comfortably as a background. Each bird carries its own presence—some mid-flight, some still, each with a quiet story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;If You’d Like to Support My Work&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This collection is free, and I’m happy to share it. But if you enjoy it and would like to support me in creating more, you can consider a small “pay-what-you-feel” donation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://buymeacoffee.com/adam.freisinger/e/374227&quot;&gt;💛 Donate (at least $1 per bird)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you do, I hope these birds find a good place to perch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-09.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/background-birds-09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;null&quot; title=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Four Weeks, Many Clamps, and an Oak Table That Stands</title>
    <link href="https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-09/coffee-table/" />
    <updated>2025-02-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://adamfreisinger.me/posts/2025-02-09/coffee-table/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-9by16&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-01.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;From 3D plans and oak planks...&quot; title=&quot;From 3D plans and oak planks...&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;From 3D plans and oak planks...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;video is-9by16&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-02.mp4&quot;&gt;
              &lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot; muted=&quot;&quot; playsinline=&quot;&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; height: 100%;&quot;&gt;
                &lt;source src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-02.mp4&quot; type=&quot;video/mp4&quot;&gt;
                Your browser does not support the video tag.
              &lt;/video&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;through lots of hours and even more clamps...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-9by16&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-03.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;with a charming character...&quot; title=&quot;with a charming character...&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;with a charming character...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-3&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-9by16&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-04.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;...to a welcoming home.&quot; title=&quot;...to a welcoming home.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;...to a welcoming home.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;And that was the moment I realised I forgot to take the oval shape into account when carefully planning the positions for the biscuits.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been so precise. I triple-checked my measurements, aligned everything, and made sure I wouldn&#39;t accidentally cut into the biscuits—only to realise too late that their placement didn’t account for the tabletop’s oval shape. And so, there they were—biscuits, peeking out right on the edge, reminding me that no matter how much I plan, reality always has a surprise in store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-08.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-08.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A shot before glue up.&quot; title=&quot;Careful planning pt. 1.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Careful planning pt. 1.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This coffee table project was filled with these moments. I started with a solid concept—Japanese and Scandinavian-inspired, heavy oak, simple but elegant lines. The design process was smooth, translating the initial vision into a 3D model, incorporating the input from the friends commissioning the table, and ensuring the proportions felt right. But from the moment I started working with the actual solid wood, things took on a life of their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Unexpected Turns&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The glue-up was intimidating. The tabletop was massive, too large for my planer, so the boards had to align perfectly. I had to redo my entire clamping setup mid-glue while the clock was ticking. Then came the jigsaw incident—blade wander forced me to trim the tabletop smaller than planned. Routing the tabletop edge? I used a handheld router, stumbled upon some end grain, and ended up cutting into what I intended to be the top, flipping the piece over and embracing the ‘backup’ side instead. Mistakes kept happening, and I kept adapting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-10.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cutting with a jigsaw.&quot; title=&quot;Does it look square?&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Does it look square?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tested different joinery methods—Lamello Clamex S-20, Festool Domino Connector, pocket hole screws with custom oak plugs—only to land on a classic, wood-and-glue-only solution. No plastic, no metal, just wood. And then, the finishing—after making a careful four-colour varnish sample board, my friends didn’t like any of them. I ended up using pigmented oil, which initially looked terrifyingly red before it settled into a deep, rich tone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-11.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oiling the table.&quot; title=&quot;A terrifying moment of no return&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A terrifying moment of no return&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even the final step—the photoshoot—had an unexpected twist. I took the table into the woods and found an abandoned, decaying hut, where the contrast between refined craftsmanship and nature’s slow reclaiming created a striking image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, I delivered the table. Minutes later, one of my friends’ small children was already using it, as if it had always been there. No ceremony, no hesitation—just immediate, everyday use. And that’s when I knew it was truly done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-06.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-06.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A detailed shot of the table&quot; title=&quot;The leg details&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;The leg details&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Workbench Notes: What I Learned&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ovals behave differently than rectangles. Plan biscuit placement accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jigsaw blades wander. I should have left more margin for error, or devised a guide rail solution for making the blade wander less.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handheld template routing a large tabletop is risky—assemble the plunge router next time for more support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I tried fastening the first Lamello Clamex S-20, the hex head practically melted away at what I felt was the slightest of forces, making the reversibility feature impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Festool Domino Connector leaves an ugly hole that’s practically impossible to plug with wood in a way that blends seamlessly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pocket hole screws with matching oak plugs were a viable option but not aesthetically ideal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final solution: solid wood floating tenons and glue—no metal, no plastic, no visible joinery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pigmented oil looks terrifying when first applied but settles into a beautiful tone. Trust the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Outdoor shoots can add a story element, especially with unexpected locations. Contrasting refined craftsmanship with raw nature makes for compelling imagery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-mobile&quot;&gt;
              &lt;div class=&quot;column is-four-fifths&quot;&gt;
                &lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-16by9&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-05.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;An oak coffee table in the woods&quot; title=&quot;Taking a stop in the woods&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Taking a stop in the woods&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project reinforced something I keep learning: I can plan, prepare, and anticipate—but at some point, I have to &lt;strong&gt;commit&lt;/strong&gt;. Spread the glue, make the cut, apply the finish, and call it done. And that’s the part I want to take with me: making final decisions doesn’t have to be terrifying. Each project builds my confidence, reminding me that I can figure things out along the way. And maybe, just maybe, the next ‘point of no return’ won’t feel quite as scary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Visual Notes:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;columns is-centered is-multiline is-mobile&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-07.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-07.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A shot after glue up.&quot; title=&quot;Careful planning pt. 2.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Careful planning pt. 2.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-09.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-09.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glue up&quot; title=&quot;Seventy bars usually help&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Seventy bars usually help&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-12.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-12.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tabletop after glue up, sander on top&quot; title=&quot;Sanding instead of planing&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Sanding instead of planing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-13.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-13.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Picture of a person sanding&quot; title=&quot;A lots of sanding ahead&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A lots of sanding ahead&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-14.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oval shape half done&quot; title=&quot;Oval shape half done&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Oval shape half done&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-15.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a handheld router&quot; title=&quot;Handheld router. Don&#39;t do this.&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Handheld router. Don&#39;t do this.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-16.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-16.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of an edge in progress&quot; title=&quot;Template routing halfway done&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Template routing halfway done&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-17.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-17.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a cut in the wood&quot; title=&quot;The intended top thus became the underside&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;The intended top thus became the underside&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-18.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oak with four different colors&quot; title=&quot;Testing varnishes&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Testing varnishes&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-19.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-19.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pencil signs on the table&quot; title=&quot;Don&#39;t forget to change the depth! :D&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Don&#39;t forget to change the depth! :D&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-20.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-20.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Festool Domino on a tabletop with mortises&quot; title=&quot;Domino in action&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Domino in action&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-21.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a miter mortise&quot; title=&quot;Angled mortises&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Angled mortises&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-22.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-22.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Making miter clamping cauls&quot; title=&quot;Making miter clamping cauls&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Making miter clamping cauls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-23.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close-up of a miter glue up&quot; title=&quot;Miter glue up at 117,25 degrees!&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Miter glue up at 117,25 degrees!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-24.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-24.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clamping setup&quot; title=&quot;A not so trivial clamping setup&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A not so trivial clamping setup&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-25.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-25.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two pieces of the table&quot; title=&quot;Ready to be joined&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Ready to be joined&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-26.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-26.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sanding dominos&quot; title=&quot;Sanding dominos for dry fitting&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Sanding dominos for dry fitting&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-27.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-27.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a crack in the wood&quot; title=&quot;Cleaning fissures with a dental probe&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Cleaning fissures with a dental probe&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-28.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-28.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fix of a crack in the wood&quot; title=&quot;A crack fixed with knot filler&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;A crack fixed with knot filler&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-29.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-29.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Close up of a crack in the wood&quot; title=&quot;Oh, more cracks...&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Oh, more cracks...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-30.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-30.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clamping setup&quot; title=&quot;Ratchet clamping FTW&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Ratchet clamping FTW&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-31.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-31.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Auro oil, pigment, wax&quot; title=&quot;Hardoils, pigment, wax&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Hardoils, pigment, wax&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-32.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-32.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sanding discs&quot; title=&quot;Not skipping grits&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Not skipping grits&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-33.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-33.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pigmented oil on oak&quot; title=&quot;Testing pigmentation&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Testing pigmentation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-34.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-34.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pigmented oils in different concentrations&quot; title=&quot;Testing pigmentation&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Testing pigmentation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-35.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-35.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Messy looking pigmenting&quot; title=&quot;Hoping that it will turn out good&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Hoping that it will turn out good&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-3by4&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-36.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-36.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The final colour of the table&quot; title=&quot;Colour of a squirrel&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Colour of a squirrel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-37.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-37.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The finished table on a workbench&quot; title=&quot;I love the grain pattern&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;I love the grain pattern&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;column is-4&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt;
                &lt;figure class=&quot;image is-4by3&quot;&gt;
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-38.jpg&quot;&gt;
              &lt;img src=&quot;https://adamfreisinger.me/assets/images/posts/coffee-table-38.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visible biscuits on the edge detail&quot; title=&quot;Oh, the biscuits!&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;/figure&gt;
                &lt;figcaption class=&quot;has-text-centered is-italic is-size-6&quot;&gt;Oh, the biscuits!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
              &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>